gear4music.com 2019-09-01

# Privacy and Cookie Policy at Gear4music

**

## SECTION 1: GENERAL

** Gear4music is fully committed to respecting your privacy and protecting any information you provide. We only use the information you provide to process orders you may place at a Gear4music website, notify you when important changes are made to our service, and occasionally tell you about relevant products or services we are offering in line with our direct marketing rules. We will not pass your details to third parties for marketing or research purposes. Please note that we may retain any data that you provide on this website, even if you do not complete your registration by clicking 'Register new account'. Such contact details and data may be used to contact you to enquire why you did not complete your registration. 

These terms can be accessed via this URL at all times, and a link to these details will be emailed to you when you have placed an order. For future reference, you may save a copy of these terms to your machine, so they may be accessed at a later date. You have the right to access your personal data and the right to correct, block and delete it at any time.

**

## 1\. What Information We Collect from You

** Our primary goal in collecting personal information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and personalised experience while using our website. This allows us to provide services and features to meet and exceed your needs and to customise our service to make your experience easier and quicker. 

To fully use our website and make purchases, you will need to register as a customer, where you will be required to provide us with your contact information and some other information required to process any orders you place with us. We automatically track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on our site. We use this information to do internal research on the interests and behaviour of our users to better understand and serve them. 

We use a web analytics tool to analyse site usage, how our users arrive at our site, what they do on the site, what browser they are using and on what operating system etc. However, this analytics data, collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site, is not tied to personally identifiable information. 

When you access our Websites via any means or make a purchase through the Website, we may collect, store and use certain of your personal information in line with this policy. To register or make a purchase on the Websites, we ask for your:  
\- name  
\- email address  
\- postal address  
\- phone contact details

When you make a purchase, our payment service providers will also collect and process your credit card or other payment details. If you contact us, we may also keep a record of that correspondence.

We may also collect data relating to your visits to the Websites that cannot identify you but records your use of our Websites including, for example, details of how long you have used the Website and Content for.

In line with current cookie regulations, we may also collect your computer’s IP address in order to help us tailor the service to your location.

Finally, we may receive information about you from third parties (such as credit reference agencies) who are legally entitled to disclose that information.

**

## 2\. Where, How and for How Long we store your Personal Data

** The information that we collect from you (including any Personal Data) may be transferred to, and stored at, various destinations. This will not include destinations outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may be processed by staff operating at various locations outside the EEA who work for us, or for one of our website development, website penetration testing (also known as “ethical hacking”), hosting, connectivity or telecommunications service providers. By providing us with your information (including Personal Data), you agree to this transfer, storing and processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not always completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your information before transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

We only use information you provide to process orders you may place at a Gear4music web site. We will keep these information as long as it is necessary under your warranty agreement, under EU and national consumer rights regulation or until relevant storage requirements from financial and tax authorities expire. When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

If you gave us your consent for inform you about our exclusive offers and discounts, we will store your details until you ask us to opt out from our direct marketing or until you exercise your right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Data in any other form.

**

## 3\. How we Use the Information that we Collect from You

** We use the information collected from you to process your order. By submitting an order your personal details will be shared with the sales, customer service and warehouse fulfilment teams at Gear4music. We also need to share your data with the relevant third-party courier companies to deliver the order to your choose delivery address. 

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only  
\- where we have your consent to do so,  
\- where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or  
\- where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights.

In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you. If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as the possible consequences if you do not provide your information). Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

We may also use your anonymised data to analyse customer activity, trends, and look at improving the customer experience and processes moving forward.

 **Our exclusive offers and discounts by email (direct marketing)**  
When you register as a new customer on the Gear4music website you have the opportunity to sign up for exclusive offers and discounts by email. By ticking the ‘accept’ box, you give us your consent to send to your registered email address our regular sales newsletter and special offers, discounts and competitions. You can always opt-out later by either: logging into your account and changing your communication preferences, clicking on the “unsubscribe” link on the bottom of our emails, or contacting our customer service department. Please note, the opt-out excludes essential service messages such as order confirmation and dispatch emails.

If you registered an account before we had the opt-in box at registration you instead had chance to opt-out from our marketing emails in compliance with the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003. As you bought something from us, gave us your contact details, and did not opt-out of marketing messages, we believe you have a legitimate interest in our products and services and are happy to receive marketing from us about similar products or services even though you haven’t specifically consented. Consequently, we will continue sending you emails after the new privacy and data protection regulations take effect on 25 May 2018. We will, of course, process your data in line with the processing principles under the new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and of course, you can opt out at any time.

 **Our abandoned checkout reminder service by email**  
If you created an account and leave the Gear4music websites with an item in the checkout basket before completing your journey, Gear4music will email you a reminder. For this service, we work with Ve Global UK Limited (Company No. 10706696) whose registered office is at White Collar Factory, Old Street Yard, London, EC1Y 8AF. Gear4music will share with Ve Global your email address, the transaction date, transaction ID and value. Gear4music and Ve Global are, together, joint controllers with you in respect of this service. Ve Global’s respective responsibilities in this regard are set out in their Privacy Policy under: https://www.ve.com/privacy-policy 

**To Whom and why we might disclose your information**  
Gear4music will never sell your data to any third party. But we may disclose your personal information to third parties when permitted by law including:  
(a) with your consent;

(b) to our suppliers in order for them to help us provide our services to you, this includes:  
\- couriers and other logistic partners that provide the delivery of goods to you;  
\- our provider of customer relationship management services (which allows us, for example, to send personalised email communications to you);  
\- our provider of file storage and management services if you email us directly;  
\- our payment services provider when you make a purchase to process your payment; and  
\- our customer service software if you contact our support team;

These suppliers’ use of your personal data may be subject to their own privacy policies, which are available on their websites, and which we suggest you familiarise yourself with in the relevant circumstances set out above.

(c) if we are under a duty to disclose or share your information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and other agreements; or to protect our rights, property, or safety, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**

## 4\. Updating your information

** You can edit any of the information in your Account. It is your responsibility:  
\- To protect against unauthorised access to your Account.  
\- To log-off from your Account when not using it.  
\- To keep your log-in details secret. 

**

## 5\. Your Rights under the Data Protection Laws

** You have certain rights under the Data Protection Laws, including:  
1\. The right at any time to withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Data.  
2\. The right to be told what Personal Data we hold about you on our database and how we process that data.  
3\. The right to request that we provide you with a copy (in a commonly used electronic format) of all the Personal Data that we hold about you. Unless you make repeated requests, we will not charge a fee for providing you with a copy of this data.  
4\. The right to request that we correct any inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data that we hold about you.  
5\. The right to request that we irretrievably delete all Personal Data that we hold about you (the so-called “right to be forgotten”). Note that there are limited circumstances in which we are legally entitled to refuse to comply with this request.  
6\. The right to request that we transmit all the Personal Data that we hold about you (in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable form) to another organisation’s IT environment. Note that we are only legally obliged to comply with this request if it is technically feasible for us to do so.

Should you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer.

If you exercise any of the above rights, then we will action your request as soon as reasonably practicable and, in any event, within one month.

**

## 6\. Links to other Websites

** Our Website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites which may be of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our Website, we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **

### 7\. Your Consent

** By agreeing to the terms of our Privacy Policy, you consent to the collection, storage, processing and sharing of your Personal Data and other information on the basis set out above.  

**

## Cookies

** We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit http://www.aboutcookies.org for detailed guidance. 

The following describes the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an 'implied consent' policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete Gear4music.com cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser's anonymous usage setting (called "Incognito" in Chrome, "InPrivate" for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc...). 

We use many cookies to enhance the shopping experience for the user, these include: 

_Advertising Cookies_  
We advertise Gear4music on a number of third party websites and ad networks, and use cookies to track which sites you clicked on. These include AdNxs, Click Fuse, Five.tv, Google Double Click, Guardian.co.uk and Rubicon Project. 

_AdWords Remarketing_  
We use a Remarketing Cookie to serve more relevant ads to users based on their behaviour during past visits to our website. Google's AdWords Remarketing connects the activity of www.gear4music.com with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie. To opt out of the cookie [click here](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/%20)

 _Affiliate Cookies_  
Allows us to track how you found Gear4music through external websites, and in some cases reward those websites. 

_Criteo_  
Provides users with personalised adverts when visiting selected other websites. These adverts are based on the products that you have been viewing on the Gear4music website, and may also show products similar to those you originally looked at. Instructions on how to prevent this kind of advertising can be found [here](http://www.criteo.com/deactivate-criteo-banners/). 

_Google Analytics_  
Provides us with information about how users use the site enabling us to improve and refine customers' experience of Gear4music. User data is all anonymous. You can find out more about Google's position on privacy as regards its analytics service at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

_QuBit_  
To ensure effective delivery of our cookies and to provide optimum user experience, we use QuBit to manage our cookies. It does not track information itself, but remembers specific tasks that we tell it to do. 

_Session Cookies_  
We use a session cookie to remember your log-in for you and what you've put in the shopping basket. These we deem strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken - including the ability to place orders. 

_Third Party Cookies_  
Some cookies used on our site are provided by third-parties, for example pages that contain embedded content, such as YouTube videos, may send you cookies. These cookies are out of our control and you should check these third-party sites for further information. 

_Sharing Tools_  
If you use social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, to share information from the Gear4music website, you may be sent cookies from these websites. These cookies are out of our control and you should check these third-party sites for further information.

**

## Your Consent

** By agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you consent to the cookies referenced above being set on your Device. 

**

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

** We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. 

**

## Data Protection Service

** You can obtain further information about data protection and privacy laws by visiting the Information Commissioner’s website at: https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/. 

**

### Integration of the Trusted Shops Trustbadge

** Following an order, the Trusted Shops Trustbadge is incorporated into the Gear4music web page in order to display our Trusted Shops trustmark for customers and the eventually collected reviews, as well as the Trusted Shops product offer. In balancing the various interests, this serves to safeguard our legitimate prevailing interests in an optimised marketing of our offer. The trustbadge and the services advertised are an offer of Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Köln, Germany. 

Whenever a trustbadge is called up, the web server automatically stores a so-called server log file which contains, for example, your IP address, the date and time of retrieval, the data volume transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the retrieval. This access data will not be evaluated and will be automatically overwritten seven days after your visit to the page. Other personal information will only be transferred to Trusted Shops if you decide, after completing an order, to use Trusted Shops products or have already registered for their use. In this case, the contractual agreement between you and Trusted Shops applies.

**

## SECTION 2: PRIVACY POLICY FOR TRADE ACCOUNT& EDUCATION ACCOUNT

** Gear4music offers the opportunity for companies, institutions and educational establishments (schools, colleges or universities) to open a trade account or an education account. These institutional accounts are not personal accounts but are linked to the relevant legal entities to which they belong. We encourage individual employees of these institutions to provide as few personal details as possible, but wherever the data of a named individual is used, that data is personal and the general rules of Section 1 of this policy apply. 

For the fulfilment of our contract with the relevant institution and with the legitimate interest of data verification and an effective business relationship with the account holder, it might be necessary to share personal information held on the institutional account with other people and departments of the same institution. Even if Gear4music aims to communicate solely with any registered main contact person, it can at its discretion, and after appropriate ID verification, also deal with other members of the account-holding institution. If an individual wants to object to this data sharing, they should do so by immediately contacting Gear4music after opening an institutional account, Gear4music may change the institutional account to a personal account to protect the individual’s privacy.

Institutional account holders must always keep their contact information up to date and must inform Gear4music immediately if registered members of staff change or leave their employment. 

**

## SECTION 3: CANDIDATES

** This section describes what information is collected by Gear4music from Candidates, and how that information is used by Gear4music. This section is solely applicable to job applications and other recruitment activities and is not relevant for other users of the website or Gear4music customers in general.

**

### 1\. What Information We Collect from You

** When you apply for a job with us (whether via the Website or otherwise), we collect and store certain pieces of Personal Data and other information relating to you, including: 

• Full name;  
• Contact details, including telephone number and email address;  
• Work history, education, skills, experience, and any other information included in your CV;  
• Details of job preferences;  
• Answers to questions that we pose to ascertain your suitability for the job for which you are applying.

We also collect and store information relating to when and how you use the Website, including (but not limited to) activity data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, although we do not knowingly collect any Personal Data as part of these activities. 

Depending on the role, Candidates will be asked to consent that their personal information will be used for the purpose of employment screening. Further details will be given in the consent declaration and its supporting documents. Gear4music is working with Know Your Candidate Ltd (Registered in England: 6872627, ICO registration: Z1860832, 1 City Approach, Albert Street, Eccles, M30 0BG), which will process the data in accordance with its privacy policy which can be viewed at www.knowyourcandidate.co.uk/privacy-policy.

**

### 2\. Where, How and for How Long we store your Personal Data

** The information that we collect from you (including any Personal Data) may be transferred to, and stored at, various destinations. This will usually not include destinations outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may be processed by staff operating at various locations outside the EEA who work for us, or for one of our website development, website penetration testing (also known as “ethical hacking”), hosting, connectivity or telecommunications service providers. By providing us with your information (including Personal Data), you agree to this transfer, storing and processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Our recruitment portal is operated by EasyWeb Group (a trading style of Verticality Ltd,) with registered address at 15-17 Strixton Manor Business Centre, Strixton, Northamptonshire, NN29 7PA, United Kingdom. The company is ISO 27001 certified and all application and data is hosted on sever in the UK with documents also stored with Amazon Web Services in Ireland. 

Personal Data will be stored on our own servers in the UK. We also use data storage services of Livedrive Internet Ltd., with registered office at The Battleship Building, 179 Harrow Road, United Kingdom, Livedrive will not transfer the files containing your Personal Data from the EEA and has implemented appropriate technical and organisational security measures designed to protect our files against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure, unauthorised access, and other unlawful or unauthorised forms of Processing, in accordance with applicable UK and European law. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not always completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your information before transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

If you apply for a role at our Manchester Officers, the recruitment team will use data management services of Trello, Inc., with offices at 55 Broadway, 25th Floor, New York NY 10006. All data is encrypted in transit and at rest. Trello services are hosted on Amazon Web Services’ (“AWS”) EC2 platform. The physical servers are located in AWS’s secure data centres. Data content can also be found in Trello backups, stored in AWS EC2, S3, Glacier, and GCS. Trello is PCI-DSS certified and is a participant in the U.S. Department of Commerce's EU-U.S. Privacy Shield program and has certified that they adhere to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles. Trello, Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. 

We will store your Personal Data for no more than one year after you stop actively using your Account, at which time your Personal Data will be irretrievably deleted. 

**

### 3\. How we Use the Information that we Collect from You

** We use the information collected from you to process your job application. By submitting a job application your personal details will be shared with the Recruitment Team at Gear4music, including any Hiring Managers involved specifically in the decision-making process. We promise to treat your personal information confidentially and only share it with authorised personnel involved in the recruitment activity. 

The lawful basis for processing your personal data is based on a legitimate interest - we need to capture this information in order to consider and process your job application. 

We may also use your anonymised data to analyse recruitment activity, trends, and look at improving recruitment activity and processes moving forward. 

**

### 4\. Updating your information

** You can edit any of the information in your Account. It is your responsibility: 

• To protect against unauthorised access to your Account.   
• To log-off from your Account when not using it.   
• To keep your log-in details secret. 

**

### 5\. Your Rights under the Data Protection Laws

** You have certain rights under the Data Protection Laws, including: 

1\. The right at any time to withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Data.   
2\. The right to be told what Personal Data we hold about you on our database and how we process that data.   
3\. The right to request that we provide you with a copy (in a commonly used electronic format) of all the Personal Data that we hold about you. Unless you make repeated requests, we will not charge a fee for providing you with a copy of this data.  
4\. The right to request that we correct any inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data that we hold about you.  
5\. The right to request that we irretrievably delete all Personal Data that we hold about you (the so-called “right to be forgotten”). Note that there are limited circumstances in which we are legally entitled to refuse to comply with this request.   
6\. The right to request that we transmit all the Personal Data that we hold about you (in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable form) to another organisation’s IT environment. Note that we are only legally obliged to comply with this request if it is technically feasible for us to do so. 

Should you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer. 

If you exercise any of the above rights, then we will action your request as soon as reasonably practicable and, in any event, within one month. You understand that the exercise of any of the rights listed may mean that we are unable to continue to process your job application.

 **

### 6\. Links to other Websites

** Our Website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites which may be of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our Website, we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.   

**

### 7\. Your Consent

** By agreeing to the terms of our Privacy Policy, you consent to the collection, storage, processing and sharing of your Personal Data and other information on the basis set out above.  

**

## SECTION 4: DATA REQUESTS BY THE POLICE OR TAX AUTHORITIES

** If you are working for the police or another public authority and need information from us for the prevention or detection of crime, the apprehension or prosecution of offenders, or the assessment or collection of tax or duty; please contact our Data Protection Officer directly under dpo@gear4music.com

Please state the name, public authority and contact details of the relevant officer making the request. For a quicker identity check, the police officer badge number is also helpful. Please explain the information which is sought and why in as much detail as possible. If we should not inform the relevant data subject about your request, please advise accordingly and give the reason. We will deal with your request as quickly as possible. Please understand that requests made in languages other than English, German, Swedish or French will take longer to process. Requests from law authorities outside the EU or EEA may take longer due to additional consultations with the UK authorities.
